Inventory of the Richard De Rochemont papers, 1900-1997
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Richard De Rochemont papers
1900-1997
De Rochemont, Richard
05940
150.11 cubic ft. (216 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
The papers of Richard De Rochemont, an American film producer and director of informational films including the March of Time newsreels.
Biography of Richard De Rochemont
Richard de Rochemont (1903-1982) was a motion picture producer and director during the twentieth century. Born in Boston, Massachusetts, and educated at Harvard University, De Rochemont started his motion picture career as a foreign editor for Fox-Movietone News (1930-1934). He joined Time Incorporated's March of Time film series, produced by Richard's brother Louis De Rochemont, in 1934 and enjoyed a notable career with this newsreel series, serving as European correspondent and managing director (1934-1940), managing director in New York City (1940-1943), and executive producer (1943-1951). As executive producer, he won an Academy Award for his production of the March of Time film "A Chance to Live" (1949). In 1955, De Rochemont founded his own film production company, Vavin Incorporated, and produced instructional films for a number of organizations between the mid 1950s and early 1980s, including the Reader's Digest Association and the French Government Tourist Office. In addition to his work in the film industry, De Rochemont was the author of several cookbooks, including Contemporary French Cooking (1962), The Pets' Cookbook (1964), and Eating in America (1976).
Scope and Content
Project files include manuscripts and articles, scripts, research files, and other documents relating to projects produced by and associated with De Rochemont. Correspondence includes subjects both personal and professional in nature. Personal and professional files include documents, research materials, membership files, newspaper clippings, engagement diaries, Vavin, Inc. records, and other files both personal and professional in scope. The films include 16mm and 35mm films produced by De Rochemont, including March of Time and films produced for the Readers Digest Association and the French Government Tourist Office. The photographs depict both De Rochemont’s personal life as well as the production of his various films, including March of Time. Audio contains reel-to-reel audio tapes, including sound for some of De Rochemont’s films.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Richard De Rochemont at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Richard De Rochemont, Jane De Rochemont (wife) and Virginia De Rochemont (niece) between 1975-2017.
Access Terms
De Rochemont, Louis, 1899-1978.; March of Time, Inc.; Reader's Digest Association.; Motion picture producers and directors -- United States -- 20th century.; Motion pictures -- Production and direction -- United States.; Documentary films -- United States -- 20th century.; Educational films -- United States -- 20th century.; Newsreels -- United States -- 20th century.; Authors, American -- 20th century.; Audiotapes.; Motion pictures.; Slides.; March of time (Motion picture).
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Performing Arts; Journalism
Container List
- Series I. Projects, 1935-1982
  Arranged alphabetically. Contains manuscripts, articles, scripts, research files, and other material related to films, books, and articles produced by De Rochemont.
  - "25 Restaurants I Like", 1975-1976 (Box 167)
  - "700 Miles of Beaches", 1957 (Box 167)
  - "Adventures of Annabelle", 1960 (Box 167)
  - Air France - "Chateaux Weather", 1951 (Box 167)
  - Air France - "Jets", 1961 (Box 167)
  - "Almanac of Will Rogers, Jr.", 1962 (Box 167)
  - "Ambassadors", circa 1952-1964 (Box 171)
  - "America's Williamsburg", 1958-1961 (Box 163)
  - American Society of Travel Agents (ASTA), 1958 (Box 167)
  - "An A.E.F. For Africa?", 1941 (Box 179)
  - Articles - by De Rochemont, 1940-1964 (Box 167)
  - Articles - by Richard De Rochemont in various periodicals, 1941-1976 (Box 194)
  - Articles - by De Rochemont on France, 1941-1945 (Box 205)
  - "Arturo", 1968 (Box 167)
  - Ballet idea, undated (Box 167)
  - "Bear", 1973 (Box 167)
  - "Blitzed America", 1941 (Box 167)
  - "Brevity Key to Larger Audience Penetration", 1963 (Box 167)
  - "Buried Treasure", undated (Box 171)
  - "Casbahs of the South", 1957 (Box 167)
  - "Cinerama", 1947-1950 (Box 167)
  - "Community Challenge", 1952-1953 (Box 167)
  - "Consumers Want To Know", 1951 (Box 167)
  - "Contemporary French Cooking", 1960-1962 (Box 169)
  - "Cornflower", 1948 (Box 167)
  - "Eating In America", 1972-1977 (Box 168-169)
  - "Eclipse", 1947 (Box 167)
  - "Essence of Sakel", undated (Box 167)
  - "Eye Witness", undated (Box 167)
  - "Filmed Encyclopedia", 1951 (Box 166)
  - Ford Foundation - "Mr. Lincoln" scripts and materials, 1952-1954 (Box 165)
  - France for Fun - "Basque Country", 1956 (Box 162)
  - France for Fun - "Normandy", 1956 (Box 162)
  - France for Fun - "Painters of Paris", 1956 (Box 162)
  - France for Fun - "Shopper's Holiday", 1956 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office, 1955-1960 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Alsace", 1959 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Artists of Provence", 1955 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Bastille Day", 1956 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Boy in Paris", 1959 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Bright New Face of Paris", 1964 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Carnival", 1956 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Chateau Country", 1955 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Contrasts of Carcassonne", 1958 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Corsica", 1959 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Diversity of France" and "Rivers of France", 1957 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Food and Wines", 1955 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "France for the Sportsman", 1958 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "French Caribbean", 1964 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "It's Convention Time…In France", 1958 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Les Baux", 1957 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Motoring Mood", 1955 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Oldest Paris", 1957 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Paris Today", 1961 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Riviera Playground", 1955 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Roussillon Folkways", 1958 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Seine Boat Ride", 1955 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Spotlight on French Spas", 1961 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Springtime in Paris", 1956 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "St. Benoit", 1957 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Summertime in the French Alps", 1958 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Vacation in France", 1956 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Welcome to France", 1964 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - "Women of France", 1958 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - Dope sheets, 1955-1964 (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - film pamphlets, undated (Box 162)
  - French Government Tourist Office - Music cue sheets, 1956-1963 (Box 162)
  - "Friday Morning in Rabat", 1957 (Box 166)
  - "Frost" (Robert Frost), 1952-1957 (Box 166)
  - "Fun Aboard the S.S. United States", 1963 (Box 166)
  - "Guggenheim Museum", 1955-1956 (Box 166)
  - "Here Is New York", 1950-1954 (Box 166)
  - History in the Writing - "Vichy vs. France", 1941 (Box 163)
  - "Houston Museum", 1963-1971 (Box 166)
  - "H-T-P Test", undated (Box 166)
  - "I Remember When", 1948 (Box 166)
  - "Jack Brink", 1963 (Box 166)
  - Jean Giraudoux", undated (Box 166)
  - "Joe Is Home Now", undated (Box 166)
  - Julius Wile Sons and Company, 1962 (Box 166)
  - "Kip Catches Up", 1965-1966 (Box 166)
  - Kodak series, 1954 (Box 165)
  - Letter to the New York Times, 1957 (Box 163)
  - Liquidation, 1967 (Box 163)
  - "Magic Mirror of Aloyse", 1964-1979 (Box 166)
  - "Man From Orbit", 1965-1966 (Box 166)
  - Marc Connelly, 1953-1960 (Box 166)
  - March of Time (MOT) - "Ballets de France" book, undated (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - "Chance to Live" newspaper clippings, 1950 (Box 199)
  - March of Time (MOT) - "Four Hours a Year: A Picture-Book Story of Time Inc.'s Third Major Publishing Venture - The March of Time", 1936 (Box 205)
  - March of Time (MOT) - "Golden Twenties" newspaper clippings, 1949-1950 (Box 199)
  - March of Time (MOT) - "Golden Twenties" promotional materials, 1950 (Box 199)
  - March of Time (MOT) - "Golden Twenties" script, undated (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - "History of the March of Time" radio script, 1942 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - "Holy Year at the Vatican" script, 1950 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - "Invitation to Harvard" script, 1951 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - "March of Time series of picture stories based on the famous films", 1942-1943 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - correspondence, 1951 (Box 178)
  - March of Time (MOT) - demise, 1951-1952 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - Europe, 1949-1951 (Box 178)
  - March of Time (MOT) - financial records, 1951 (Box 178)
  - March of Time (MOT) - Forum Films synopses, 1950-1951 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - Museum of Modern Art, 1942-1951 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - operating and personnel data (Box 206)
  - March of Time (MOT) - photo book, undated (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - photo collage, undated (Box 213)
  - March of Time (MOT) - photographic collage, undated (Box 205)
  - March of Time (MOT) - Project Y, 1947 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - publicity materials and posters, undated (Box 205)
  - March of Time (MOT) - scripts (volumes 1-17), 1942-1951 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - synopses, 1935-1951 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - testimonial letters, 1943-1947 (Box 161)
  - March of Time (MOT) - Vichy cables, 1940-1941 (Box 178)
  - March of Time (MOT) - Vichy, 1940-1946 (Box 178)
  - March of Time (MOT) - wooden plaque, undated (Box 205)
  - Material for book, undated (Box 162)
  - Mexico contracts and negatives, 1963 (Box 162)
  - "Michael Tanguy", 1961 (Box 166)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 162)
  - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Pisqui", 1967 (Box 164)
  - Montici - "Intarsia", 1958 (Box 166)
  - "Morocco", 1957 (Box 166)
  - Morrow autobiography, 1977 (Box 166)
  - Motion picture scripts, undated (Box 163)
  - "Motorama", 1956 (Box 166)
  - "Mr. Lincoln" newspaper clippings, 1952 (Box 199)
  - "Murder at Smutty Nose", undated (Box 166)
  - "Mysteries of Islam", 1957 (Box 166)
  - "Mysteries of Paris", 1955 (Box 166)
  - N.A.A.C.P., 1954-1959 (Box 164)
  - National Homes - "Astrohome", 1969 (Box 167)
  - "No Taps For Airman Anderson", 1962-1964 (Box 164)
  - Notes on French politics, 1941-1946 (Box 166)
  - Notes on works in progress, undated (Box 162)
  - "Oyster Bay", 1963 (Box 164)
  - "Paris Grapevine", undated (Box 164)
  - "Party at the Potters", 1956 (Box 164)
  - "Party Line", 1943-1950 (Box 164)
  - "Penney-Houston House", 1972 (Box 164)
  - "Perfect Club Dining Room", 1965 (Box 164)
  - "Pet's Cookbook", 1962-1964 (Box 170)
  - "Pit and the Century Plant", 1955-1967 (Box 164)
  - Play outline, undated (Box 164)
  - Poem, undated (Box 164)
  - Portugal, 1941-1942 (Box 164)
  - "Prisoner", undated (Box 164)
  - Production crossplot for "Star!", 1967 (Box 205)
  - Propaganda pamphlets, 1938, 1977-1982 (Box 164)
  - Reader's Digest scripts, circa 1959-1969 (Box 163)
  - Rejected manuscripts and discarded notes, undated (Box 162)
  - "Rendezvous With Glamour", 1941-1945 (Box 163)
  - Research files - food, 1959-1975 (Box 188)
  - Research files - French wines, 1950-1964 (Box 188)
  - Reynold's Metals Company - closed circuit, undated (Box 163)
  - "Sade, J'Ecris Ton Nom Liberte", undated (Box 163)
  - "Salbris", 1942 (Box 163)
  - Short stories, undated (Box 163)
  - "Signposts for a Two-Way Street", 1959-1960 (Box 163)
  - "Sporting Vacations", 1957 (Box 163)
  - "Sultan", 1957 (Box 163)
  - "Theatre of Étienne Decroux", 1961-1964 (Box 167)
  - "Thing He Loves", undated (Box 163)
  - "Threshold", undated (Box 163)
  - Town & Country - "The Bacchic Brotherhood", October - November 1964 (Box 216)
  - Underground article notes, circa 1942 (Box 179)
  - United States - Germany, 1946-1947 (Box 163)
  - Untitled, 1941 (Box 162)
  - "Virginia Museum", 1961 (Box 163)
  - Vita Films - TV-Radio workshop film catalog, 1952-1955 (Box 163)
  - "Welcome to France" production materials, circa 1959 (Box 199)
  - World Assembly of Youth scripts, 1952 (Box 163)
  - "World Without Flowers", 1973 (Box 163)
  - WWII - statement of German surrender, 1945 (Box 163)
- Series II. Correspondence, 1932-1982
  Arranged alphabetically. Contains personal and professional correspondence with both individuals and organizations.
  - A, 1945-1981 (Box 159)
  - Apartment 235, E. 46th, 1941-1974 (Box 159)
  - Automobiles, 1963-1971 (Box 159)
  - B, 1955-1981 (Box 159)
  - Beha, Rene, 1938-1943 (Box 154)
  - Benoit-Levy, 1945-1960 (Box 158)
  - Berger, Eric, 1980 (Box 154)
  - Bernard Reis and Company - accountants, 1946-1964 (Box 154)
  - Bernstein and Weiss, 1968-1979 (Box 159)
  - Bruyere, Gaby, 1960-1961 (Box 158)
  - C, 1949-1979 (Box 159)
  - Capa, Robert, 1946 (Box 158)
  - Christmas cards and letters, 1970-1973, undated (Box 154)
  - CIDALC, 1962 (Box 158)
  - Clofine, M.D., 1943-1973 (Box 158)
  - Commanderie de Bordeaux, 1960-1970 (Box 159)
  - Commanderie des Cordons Bleus, 1971-1976 (Box 159)
  - Compte, Mr. Gilbert (March of Time), 1949-1950 (Box 154)
  - Congratulations, 1943-1961 (Box 154)
  - D, 1945-1978 (Box 159)
  - Davidson, Jo, 1948-1949 (Box 158)
  - De Chambrun, Rene, 1972 (Box 158)
  - De Gaulle Institute, 1974 (Box 159)
  - De Gaulle, 1947 (Box 158)
  - De Kay, Ormonde, 1958-1962 (Box 154)
  - De Rochemont, Helen - condolences, 1975 (Box 160)
  - De Rochemont, Helen Bentley Bogart - wills, 1968 (Box 157)
  - De Rochemont, Helen Bentley Bogart, 1955-1972 (Box 158)
  - De Rochemont, Louis Sr. - estate, 1939-1943 (Box 154)
  - De Rochemont, Louis, 1943-1979 (Box 154)
  - De Rochemont, Louis, 1950-1969 (Box 160)
  - De Rochemont, Nicole, 1971-1976 (Box 159)
  - De Rochemont, Richard/Helen, 1957-1960 (Box 154)
  - De Rochemont, S.W., 1942-1944 (Box 160)
  - De Rochemont, Sarah, 1941-1947 (Box 155)
  - De Rochemont, Virginia, 1978-1982 (Box 216)
  - Delaunay, Sonia, undated (Box 159)
  - Douglas, Mr. and Mrs. Fred, 1946-1975 (Box 158)
  - Douze Gueules, 1975 (Box 159)
  - Dreyfus, Michael, 1960-1973 (Box 158)
  - E, 1965-1978 (Box 159)
  - E.O.A. contracts, 1974-1975 (Box 159)
  - Europe, 1973-1977 (Box 158-159)
  - Explorers Club, 1965-1968 (Box 159)
  - F, 1951-1979 (Box 159)
  - Family, 1979-1982 (Box 154)
  - Ford Foundation, 1956-1974 (Box 154)
  - France, 1958-1979 (Box 158-159)
  - Free France, 1941-1942 (Box 154)
  - G, 1950-1972 (Box 159)
  - Gershwin, Ira, 1942 (Box 154)
  - Gilbert, Compte, 1951 (Box 154)
  - Gilligan, 1953-1973 (Box 158)
  - Glenn, Jack - obituary, 1981 (Box 154)
  - Gratz, L., 1946-1950 (Box 158)
  - H, 1951-1981 (Box 159)
  - Handel, 1951-1974 (Box 159)
  - Harvard Club of New York, 1941-1973 (Box 159)
  - Harvard Reunion, 1967-1975 (Box 159)
  - Holtzman, Mr. and Mrs. George, 1944-1970 (Box 158)
  - J, 1941-1976 (Box 159)
  - J. Walter Thompson Company, 1955 (Box 158)
  - Jaffe Agency, 1952-1953 (Box 158)
  - K, 1951-1971 (Box 159)
  - L, 1963-1981 (Box 156)
  - Lancaster, H. Maurice (London), 1949-1975 (Box 158)
  - Larsen, Roy E., 1948-1972 (Box 158)
  - Lazard-Mayer dossier, 1945 (Box 154)
  - Letters of complaint, 1977-1981 (Box 154)
  - Luce, Henry R., 1944-1949 (Box 158)
  - Lye, Len (March of Time), 1945-1973 (Box 155)
  - M, 1949-1977 (Box 156)
  - Makohins, Mr. and Mrs. Lee J. (Princess Razumowski), 1941-1965 (Box 158)
  - Mangan, Sherry, 1941-1977 (Box 156)
  - Martelliere, 1952-1974 (Box 156)
  - Mayor Impellitteri, 1951-1952 (Box 158)
  - McIntyre, William and Malvina, 1941-1970 (Box 160)
  - Medical, 1947-1977 (Box 156)
  - Miro, Joan, 1977 (Box 156)
  - Miscellaneous, 1943-1982 (Box 154-155)
  - Miscellaneous, 1944-1978 (Box 160)
  - Moulin, 1976-1978 (Box 156)
  - Moulin construction, 1965-1966 (Box 156)
  - Moulin-Pinellis, 1976-1982 (Box 160)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1941-1971 (Box 155)
  - N, 1963-1973 (Box 156)
  - New York Plaza, 1973 (Box 156)
  - New Yorker, 1932 (Box 155)
  - O, 1944-1976 (Box 156)
  - Office of Strategic Services, 1942 (Box 155)
  - OPC Fund, 1968-1975 (Box 156)
  - P, 1942-1971 (Box 156)
  - Pabst Brewing company - commercial, 1947 (Box 159)
  - Pages, Jean, 1943-1957, 1969 (Box 155-156)
  - Paris-American Club, 1966-1968 (Box 155)
  - Payroll household, 1981-1982 (Box 156)
  - Personal, 1938-1979 (Box 155)
  - Personal, 1939-1975 (Box 160)
  - Phillipe, C.C., 1958-1960 (Box 160)
  - Photostats, undated (Box 156)
  - Ponnelle, 1946-1961 (Box 160)
  - Prominent individuals (copies), circa 1943-1965 (Box 181)
  - Prominent individuals (originals), circa 1943-1965 (Box 215)
  - R, 1946-1979 (Box 156)
  - Rattner film, 1953 (Box 155)
  - Rattner, Abe, 1944-1974 (Box 160)
  - Rebiere, Marcel (Paris), 1940-1970 (Box 155-156)
  - Reis, undated (Box 156)
  - Renoir, Jean, 1940-1941 (Box 160)
  - Rochemont, Mme. Veuve, 1969-1970 (Box 160)
  - Root, Waverley, 1949-1982 (Box 155-156)
  - Root, Waverley, 1943-1956 (Box 160)
  - Root, Waverley - Eating in America, 1975-1979 (Box 156)
  - Roquefort, 1980 (Box 156)
  - S, 1940-1981 (Box 157)
  - Santino Sozio, 1943-1948 (Box 160)
  - Schwob, Andre, 1941-1979 (Box 157)
  - Scott Graphics and 3M, 1976-1979 (Box 157)
  - Sicaud, 1948-1978 (Box 160)
  - Sky Club, 1943-1977 (Box 157)
  - Social Security and Medicare, 1974-1980 (Box 157)
  - Societe Immobillere Raspail Beausejour, 1965-1975 (Box 155)
  - Sonnenberg, Mr. and Mrs. Benjamin, 1945-1971 (Box 160)
  - Stanley, James, 1980 (Box 155)
  - Stocks - commercial - Motion Picture Association, 1946 (Box 157)
  - Stultz, Mr. and Mrs. Joseph, 1957-1978 (Box 157)
  - Stultz, Mr. and Mrs. Joseph, 1966-1971 (Box 160)
  - Subscriptions, 1968-1973 (Box 157)
  - Surrogate papers, 1975-1976 (Box 159)
  - T, 1952-1977 (Box 157)
  - Time cables - Vichy, 1941-1942 (Box 160)
  - U, 1975-1979 (Box 157)
  - V, 1946-1975 (Box 157)
  - Vandivert, Bill and Rita, 1945-1976 (Box 157)
  - Vavin, Alexis (pseudonym), undated (Box 157)
  - Vavin, Incorporated, 1948-1951 (Box 157)
  - Veterans of Strategic Services, 1951-1972 (Box 157)
  - Vichy, 1940-1943 (Box 160)
  - W, 1946-1978 (Box 157)
  - Waldorf Astoria, 1974 (Box 157)
  - Wartime communications, 1939-1940 (Box 160)
  - Weill, Lucie, 1980-1982 (Box 155)
  - Weill, Lucie and Pierre Andre, 1956-1979 (Box 155)
  - Weill, Pierre Andre and Paul, 1946-1975 (Box 157)
  - Wells, J.C., Limited, 1974 (Box 157)
- Series III. Personal and professional files, 1916-1982
  Arranged alphabetically. Contains documents, research materials, membership files, newspaper clippings, engagement diaries, Vavin, Inc. records, and other files both personal and professional in scope.
  - Advertisement, undated (Box 177)
  - Art - subject file, 1951-1978 (Box 177)
  - Art gallery - La Galerie Art Vivant, 1949-1971 (Box 180)
  - Book - "Audience of Time Presented Through the Curious and Antique Science of Heraldry", undated (Box 205)
  - Books - Boston University alumni catalogue, 1918 (Box 193)
  - Books - Harvard class of 1894 anniversary reports, 1919-1944 (Box 193)
  - Books - Harvard class of 1928 anniversary reports, 1929-1978 (Box 193)
  - Books - Louis De Rochemont's Windjammer, 1958 (Box 194)
  - Books - Time-Life history and photo books, 1927-1979 (Box 194)
  - Books - various - signed by authors to De Rochemont, 1930-1974 (Box 192)
  - Books - Williams College yearbook, 1922 (Box 193)
  - By-laws, undated (Box 177)
  - Calling cards, undated (Box 176)
  - Cheradame, Andre, 1943 (Box 174)
  - Cherasse - La Gazette, 1966-1967 (Box 178)
  - De Gaulle, 1944-1960 (Box 174)
  - Document cards, undated (Box 206)
  - European diary, 1938-1975 (Box 177)
  - Family tree, undated (Box 216)
  - Financial, circa 1931-1933 (Box 178)
  - Financial - diversion payments, 1966-1973 (Box 178)
  - Financial - expenses, circa 1941 (Box 178)
  - Financial - French taxes, 1940 (Box 178)
  - Financial - Time employees, 1944-1948 (Box 178)
  - Franco-American Audio-Visual Distribution Center, 1953 (Box 174)
  - Free French Press and Information Service, 1943-1948 (Box 175)
  - French Consulate General, 1945-1946 (Box 174)
  - French Embassy, 1945-1955 (Box 174)
  - French press - report on, 1946 (Box 174)
  - French Provisional Government, 1943-1944 (Box 174)
  - Government documents - CIA file on De Rochemont, circa 1942-1978 (Box 177)
  - Government documents - Department of Justice file on De Rochemont, 1944-1945 (Box 177)
  - Government documents - draft status, 1943-1944 (Box 177)
  - Government documents - FBI file on De Rochemont, circa 1942-1976 (Box 177)
  - Government documents - Loyalty Board question, 1954 (Box 177)
  - Government documents - United States Government Security Clearance, 1953-1954 (Box 177)
  - Herriot, undated (Box 178)
  - Identity cards, undated (Box 176)
  - Ilma's Grapevine, 1954 (Box 178)
  - Index of Richard De Rochemont films, undated (Box 178)
  - Langan Aperture Cards, Inc. (LAC), 1971-1977 (Box 183)
  - Laugier dinner, 1946 (Box 174)
  - Magazine clippings, circa 1958-1966 (Box 178)
  - Marseilles, 1941 (Box 178)
  - Mental illness treatment pamphlets, 1944, 1962 (Box 178)
  - Mental illness treatment reprints, 1954, 1959 (Box 178)
  - Miscellaneous, 1930-1980 (Box 179)
  - Monde Uni, 1946 (Box 175)
  - Musical composition - "Now", 1943 (Box 178)
  - New York Restaurants, 1975 (Box 179)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 179)
  - Newspaper clippings - French newspapers, 1945-1950 (Box 189-191)
  - Newspaper clippings - miscellaneous, undated (Box 189)
  - Organizations - ALCAN - France Libre, 1941-1975 (Box 174)
  - Organizations - American War Correspondents Association, 1944-1949 (Box 177)
  - Organizations - Americans For France, 1941 (Box 174)
  - Organizations - Association of Free French in the United States, 1954-1978 (Box 174)
  - Organizations - Bouviers and Briards, 1944-1946 (Box 177)
  - Organizations - Chevaliers du Tastevin, 1961-1977 (Box 185)
  - Organizations - Copper Hill Golf Club, 1970 (Box 178)
  - Organizations - Fighting French Delegation, 1942 (Box 174)
  - Organizations - France Forever, 1941-1948 (Box 174-175)
  - Organizations - Free French, 1945-1946 (Box 174)
  - Organizations - French book club, 1947 (Box 178)
  - Organizations - French Committee - New York War Fund, 1944 (Box 174)
  - Organizations - French Committee - Red Cross, 1944 (Box 174)
  - Organizations - French-American Club, 1941-1946 (Box 175)
  - Organizations - Institut Charles De Gaulle, 1973-1974 (Box 178)
  - Organizations - Manfred Sakel Foundation, 1958-1968 (Box 178)
  - Organizations - Merite Nationale, 1979 (Box 178)
  - Organizations - Mme. De Gaulle's Children's Fund, 1945 (Box 178)
  - Organizations - Overseas Press Club, 1943-1974 (Box 172-173)
  - Organizations - Red Cross, 1941 (Box 179)
  - Organizations - Society of the Silurians - New York, 1964-1969 (Box 179)
  - Personal - address books, undated (Box 176)
  - Personal - awards, 1950, 1962 (Box 177)
  - Personal - biographical information, circa 1924-1978 (Box 177)